Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Mo...ther…
What's wrong ?
Why don't you shoot ?
I said I'd spare both Garmillas and Earth.
What's the meaning of this, Mill ?
Before taking over your memories and despair
from the last thousand years, I want to ascertain…
…if human desire is truly so weak that it can
be changed through immediate gratification.
I've been created to become the Emperor.
My words are Zorder's words.
Now, young Desler...
...choose your future.
Shoot, Ranhalt.
Mill is not lying.
You should know that.
A man of the Desler family must not hesitate.
Obtain what's necessary regardless of the sacrifice.
Führer…
Don't !
Kodai !
It's the same test I had to take before.
Whether you pull the trigger or not,
you'll lose something important.
You shouldn't choose.
The moment when you choose...
...you lose.
If you don't choose, what's the point ?!
The enemy's mobile weapons have gone silent !
The assault team must have done it.
Commander…
In the end, it's all the same.
You're still pulling the trigger,
only now it's a different target.
That's right.
Humans have always chosen to pull the trigger…
…deceiving ourselves and believing that that's
the only way to survive or save an ally.
We'll continue pulling the trigger.
The debt must be paid by someone…
…who's capable of doing
so when the time is right.
I want peace.
I will surrender to you if necessary.
Take this, suckers.
Even if you detonate me,
it's only going to make a flicker in space.
You don't understand, do you ?
Death is not the hardest thing for humans.
No one else will be hurt here...
Idiot !
Don't die alone !
Don't you get it ?!
They want a sad ending like this !
You moron, get away !
They'll kill you, too !
They might as well do it, then !
They can't destroy anything !
Not the Yamato, not Earth,
not even one human soul !
Right, Commander ?
Even someone like me
doesn't have to die alone.
You shouldn't…
You shouldn't die alone.
You have to do everything you
can to be satisfied before you die.
If you don't die as a human you lose.
You're the commander !
Don't lose !
You think you're the first one ?
Every civilization has a
person who thinks like you.
We have a fitting response for those people.
If you think of him as your friend,
don't put him to shame.
Even so…
Even so, one side has to choose
the path of not pulling the trigger.
Not pull the trigger ?
If you could simply do that...
...no one would suffer.
The choice has been made.
You'll atone for your decision with your blood !
Yu…
Yuki…
Yuki !
Hang on, Yuki...
You're alright...
...Yuki.
Why ?
Yuki…
Kodai…
Yuki, why ?
I don't know.
I don't know, but…
…I'm glad.
Why…?
She should have lost her memories.
She doesn't know him.
It's almost like she's in love with him.
You once said human love is a mere
electrical signal passing through the brain.
Humans value it in their heart and soul because
they need its comfort to escape from their misery.
That's something we haven't
figured out about humans.
The Type Zorder has a superior brain, and it's fated to retain the memories of all previous incarnations.
Let's listen to him.
It could be something we've been waiting
to hear for the last thousand years.
This body may only be a vessel...
But there's something else.
It's none other than a soul.
And it binds humans…
…as strong as gravity.
There's no doubt.
Your Majesty, you must have known this.
The past Zorder models differ slightly, even
though they retain all the past memories.
We Gatlantians are also humans with unique souls.
We're brought together by fate, and
live to weave the threads of love.
I want to find out the reason.
We know so little about…
...humans...
...and ourselves.
This is not the time to draw a conclusion.
If we can start over…
If we can look to a different future by freeing
ourselves from the past thousand years…
…then we should.
I should choose the
path of not pulling the trigger.
Mill…
Führer, I'm glad you're safe !
Our fleet's waiting ! Please hurry !
This is...
This is too foolish.
We had a god-given opportunity...
...and we wasted it.
This war will only end one way.
Ko…
I wish I could have met him
under different circumstances.
You can't choose fate.
I need your help.
This war won't end until one side is annihilated.
Even so, all I can do now is to pass on
the hope that the young Zorder gave me.
Are you going ?
The future of mankind throughout
the universe is at stake in this war.
I can't turn away.
I entrust the future of Garmillas to you.
Knowing how futile war is, please
lead our people to a new planet.
Tell Kodai…
My Neu Deusular will protect the Yamato from the radiant energy from the transit wave motion gun, so keep up.
Why did we fight…?
Why didn't we try to love each other ?
What's wrong ?
What happened ?
Nothing.
I just took a bath.
What do you mean ? Why ?
Don't tell me…
You're Gatlantis's...
This's the only way to cut the
strings from the puppet, right ?
How much were you exposed ?
I still have one more battle left in me.
Emergency message from the Mars Garmillas fleet !
"Warp barrier has been breached, and the
White Comet is advancing toward Earth" !
Earthlings, I have pleasant news.
We of Gatlantis will not destroy Earth.
Because of its value, Earth will
become a part of the Comet Empire.
The Time Fault is worthless to you.
It only works effectively when it's
integrated with the Ark of Destruction.
Sunlight will no longer shine on this planet.
The lands and oceans will
will no longer sustain life.
From now on, you'll be living
off of our offerings only.
The Comet Empire has demanded
unconditional surrender…
Give respect to the great emperor.
Pledge your loyalty if you want to live.
Those with beneficial skills will
have the honor of living as slaves.
Hey, what happened to the Yamato ?
Once the Yamato comes back,
it can beat them, right ?
Right ?
Yamato…
That's right, the Yamato…
Wasn't it destroyed already ?
It's not listed with the lost fleet.
It's still operational ?
That's right.
We still have the Yamato !
Yamato…
Episode 23
Soldiers of Love
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki :
Yasuo Nanbu:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Sado Sakezo:
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Kurata Masaru:
Katsuragi Touko:
Hijikata Ryu:
Todo Heikuro:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Shigeru
Tochi Hiroyuki
Amagai Kazusa
Kiyohito Yoshikai
Kaida Yuko
Kusumi Naomi
Kojima Toshihiko
Abelt Desler:
Klaus Keyman:
Garmillas Soldier:
Zorder:
Gailane:
Geniz:
Mill:
News Caster:
Boy:
Male Citizen:
Female Citizen:
Yamadera Koichi
Kamioya Hiroshi
Karasuda Hiroshi
Tezuka Hideaki
Shibata Hidekatsu
Umetsu Hideyuki
Uchiyama Koki
Nokubi Naoko
Miura Ayano
Katsunuma Kento
Okumura Mei
Togire yuku manazashi wa...
Your fading gaze turns to...
...Yuuja no tashika na rashinban
...a trusted compass of a warrior
Yakusoku wa nai mama ni...
Without any promise...
...Yatsura mo ikari wo agedasu
...they will weigh anchor in response
Kowarekaketa kono sekai wa...
The half-destroyed world has named...
...Te wo sashinoberu hito no na wo
...the people who can lend a hand
Namari iro no kotae ga...
A lead-colored response...
...Kurayami ni tsumetaku tsukihanasu
...cut coldly through the darkness
Inochi wo tsumuide tokoshie no tami
Spin the thread of life for the everlasting journey
Kibou no kuni e
To the nation of hope
Otoko no sadame ni seigi tsuranuki
Stay faithful to justice in men's destiny
Torawareta ashita wo sukuu no sa
Save the besieged future
Shuuen ni mukaeba itsuka rifujin na sekai ga...
When the end comes near, the unexpected world will...
...Kurenai no sakazuki de otagai no yuuki tataeyou
...cheer both sides with a crimson cup
Hakai to souzou densetsu no kake...
Destruction and creation, and legendary wagers...
...Yatsura mo onaji sa
...fall onto both sides
Tatakai no hibuta
The outbreak of war
Towa ni kirarete honou no okite
It repeats endlessly in a destined blaze
Kodoku to shouri ga korogariochiru...
Loneliness and victory will eventually be known...
...Mekuru meku uchuu no hate made
...throughout dazzling space
Preview
We're born alone, and die alone.
Why do people meet ?
Kodai, you are the next captain.
Episode 24
Yamato, Seize the Comet Empire!